Welcome in to Free Agency Fridays. We
are here with Charles Omenu in the Big
Bear AI Command Center studio, our
newest edge rusher, my brother. How are
you feeling?
>> I feel good, man. I feel blessed. I feel
appreciated. I'm thankful to be here.
>> Congratulations, man. This is a big
deal. Nothing's promised in the NFL, but
you've made it this far and man, it's
been impressive. I think I read 23
career sacks so far. Now you're bringing
your talents here to Washington, man.
Why the Commanders? Um, I think just AP
and Coach Quinn,
>> um, Coach Henderson, my dog T, Coach
Tap, Pat, I just, there's a lot of guys
I know in this building. Um, uh, their
plan for me. They they really
illustrated a plan that I really can see
myself excelling and really getting back
to that peak performance or even better
than what I was um, my year, my first
year in Kansas City and my last year
with the Niners. those years just kind
of keep reminis reminiscing in my head
because I'm like that needs to be the
standard and consistent and better.
>> So, I think this style of defense is
going to unlock that. And uh you know,
it's always it always is really really
cool, bro, when um a staff,
>> you know, facetimes you before you sign.
Like they're they're recruiting you to
come and like they're making you feel
like, "Hey, we want you here. Like
you're very very wanted. We have this
plan for you. This is what it is." that
kind of feeling, you just can't bypass
it. And then I got my big dog LT here.
>> Yeah.
>> So, uh, the family is here, bro. So, it
just, it made sense.
>> Yeah. And then when you look around the
league, right, edge rushers are a big
big deal. And we knew it was a major
major deal here, the commanders. And you
said they talked to you kind of about
how they'll be utilizing you, man. Can
you share a little bit with us and what
are those things that stood out that
made you say, "Oh, here I can get back
to my old self."
>> Yeah, I mean, they just basically just
told me you'll be rushing all up and
down the line. um being used all up and
down the line, you know, primarily
inside, but you know, you could rush the
center, you could rush the guard, you
could rush the tackle, like run games.
It's very interchangeable pieces. And
that's why I think um when I was coming
out of the draft was kind of like my big
thing, like, hey, he can he has no
limitation on the defensive line.
>> So, um that kind of playing and it being
like an attack style is something that
really really intrigued me. And um I
think it's going to give me the
opportunity to flourish and just um in a
sense just be happy again and like feel
like all the hard work I put in
offseason. I really really dedicate
myself in the offseason, man. Uh I
really have a detailed plan when I'm
when I'm working um Monday through
Friday. It's it's it's a grind for me.
So um I want that hard work to pay off.
>> Do you feel like you lost your happiness
at some point?
>> Um a little bit.
>> Yeah. My happiness comes from success,
man. Um, you know, team success for
sure, but at the same time, like you got
you using this to feed your family, you
know.
>> Yeah.
>> And you using this to create a legacy
and uh you using this to make your
people feel happy. And so when you know,
you're in a space where you feel like
you're kind of struggling, it can be
difficult. But um uh God makes a way.
God has a plan. God never has forsaken
me. Uh there's a lot of battles that
I've I've I've fought and I've came up
on top and I'm here speaking to you
today. Um from a fifth round pick to
year eight in the league. Um three
contracts in the league. I've gotten a
major big I've gotten a big contract
before and I'm trying to get back to
that and I think the Commanders will be
a great place for me and you know uh
hopefully this is my last stop.
>> Oh man, we love that. We want you to be
home here man. You mentioned the word
success. What does success look like for
Charles and many of you?
>> Uh winning and contributing to winning.
Um, everybody loves to win. I love to
win. And the more you win, the bigger
games you're in, and the bigger games
you're in, the bigger the spotlight. And
I think this organization, this city
deserves that. Um, I know two years ago
you guys were right there. Um, you know,
and and that was a really, really good
team that you guys had, you know. So,
um, getting back to that and getting
over the hump cuz, you know, y'all had
the the Hail Mary, y'all had all lot a
lot of crazy things, you know, and I
know it brought a lot of energy to the
building.
>> So, with the players that are coming in
here, I think it's it's it's it's lined
up, bro. Obviously, we got to put in the
work, but I can't lie to you. On paper,
this one of the most impressive just
front seven I've been a part of. Truly.
>> That's very interesting you say that
because you've been on the biggest
stage, man. you have won a Super Bowl.
So, when you look at this team and this
roster as it is now, because you were
one of those like last pieces that we're
bringing in to kind of finish this
puzzle,
>> do you see parallels to the previous
Super Bowl team you're on to this kind
of team and this kind of roster with the
personnel you have with the coaching
staff? Cuz I know it takes all of those
things to make a Super Bowl champion.
>> Yeah. I I think I would compare this to
like when I was with the Niners
>> cuz just a lot of defensive line talent
a lot.
>> Yeah. you know, and obviously we all
just got to tap in and really get going
and hone in. And it starts in OTAAS. I
know OTAAS is like, ah, it's OTAAS, but
you know, with a new st with a new
defensive staff, um, new defensive
system, I think that continuity and guys
getting here and really learning each
other is going to be a big thing. And
yeah, I just think it's a lot of talent
on the on on in the outside linebacker
room and the interior D line room. I
just think it's a lot of talent, bro.
And it's
it it it mirrors that kind of talent
that had in the niners. And then also
like with the Chiefs like we I think we
were very like topheavy. So we had guys
who you know me and Chris and George and
Mike and we were very very topheavy and
we were really good. So those two teams
kind of just mirror as far as like that
defensive line depth and talents there.
>> And with all that depth and talent, how
does somebody like you stand out from
the pack? What makes you different than
all the other defensive line, not just
on this team, but in the NFL? that I can
just be anywhere. Uh I don't have a
limitation where I can rush at.
>> Like I can rush the center, I can rush
in two, I can rush in three, I can rush
in four, five, six, seven, nine. Um as
far as in the run game, I can play a
four eye and out. Um I could play the
three. But
>> coaching, you know, like we got big
guys.
>> Yeah. So you good. You got to do that.
>> But if I had to, I could. I've done it.
Um
>> so I I've have no limitations as far as
where I can line up at, honestly. I feel
comfortable lining up anywhere.
>> And I think that's something that Dvonte
Jones, our new defensive coordinator, he
he prides himself in having players that
are versatile like that. What have those
conversations been like with your new
defensive coordinator?
>> Yeah. No, it's been a big time about
versatility big time about, hey man, I
see you can be here, here, here, and
different pairings and m and matchups
and stuff like that. That excites me.
It's like, man, I really can just take
advantage of wherever the spot I'm at.
Like, you just not dictated in one spot.
and with one singular type of movement.
It's like, bro, you could be here, be
here. We can run a game, you can twist
up, and it's it's it's going to be fun.
>> What's your goals for this year, man?
You've accomplished so much already. You
are coming off of a strong year. What is
your goal for yourself this year?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think my goal first and
foremost is to help this team win
>> as much as possible.
>> And it starts off winning the division.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, this is a very historic division,
NFC East. Uh, I grew up in Texas, so
>> Oh, did you? Unfortunately, I grew up a
fan of the other team, that team in
Texas.
>> You know, you're smart to not say the
name, man. I pe I peaked that, man. Good
stuff.
>> But, um, uh, my I'm here, right? And,
you know, that you got to win this
division. Winning the division is a big
thing. And like I said, with the talent
and depth that we have, I feel like it's
very, very feasible. Um, and then
individually,
I want to have my best year of my career
bar none. Like, that is my mentality. um
after kind of like this you know happy
feeling of no hey I'm signed d once that
that will be done as soon as I leave
here
>> and my mindset will be how can I be the
best Charles men who for the commanders
>> and if I'm the best Charles Moo in my
career for the commanders I think I'll
be a very big key to helping us win
>> and I mean to be your best self that
takes a lot of work that takes a lot of
preparation what kind of work and
preparation have you been putting in to
be ready for this moment
>> yeah I mean now I have a I've hired a
full-time chef I've had se full-time
like year around. Um, I add a
nutritionist year round. Um, I kind of
like I like working out with guys, but I
think
uh for me working out in the offseason
by myself makes it me versus me. Um,
where that you can't run around the
system, you can't talk your way out of a
set or blabber with your homeboy. So,
like I have u my own personal PT and
trainer. Um and then uh I go out there
and we I started kind of like defensive
line work a little earlier.
>> Yeah.
>> To sharpen my tool on that space and um
um I I've continued to just kind of work
on my body and and maintain myself. So I
just have really just said, you know,
we're going to dial in on you
>> like what are what be honest yourself.
What are your weaknesses and attack
those?
>> Where does that come from? Right? like
where do you say okay the nutrition this
is important the working out cuz it
seems like all of this stuff is fairly
new for you things that you're trying
different is there a player you played
with that inspired you to say hey man
this is how you really lock in
>> I think I think these are things I've
done but I think me making it very
individualized
>> um and putting that kind of resource in
is where it's new um and yeah JJ
>> Watt
>> JJ Watt has been honest like like a guy
that I looked up to when I came in the
league because he was just so dominant,
but he put in all that time and he made
a a a major thing to take care of his
body. So, I really really was inspired
that by that. And then uh Eric Armstead
when I went to San Fran and Nick Bosa in
San Francisco, those two guys um Bosa
was the one that really got me on like
working out four times a week in the
season. Um and so and he got me on front
squat. He got me a lot of stuff. Just
kind of just going after practice and
working out by yourself or working out
with another guy, bringing guys in
>> and Kenla can can tell you about that
cuz he was in there with us.
>> Yeah.
>> So that those things just um are things
where I just feel like I'm just going to
carry over and keep going because it's a
blessing to be your eight, but I want I
want to play this thing until the wheels
fall off. Man,
>> I'm glad you mentioned Kinlaw because I
think a lot of people don't realize that
you guys do have overlap and you guys
>> have played together before. Did he rap
with you about what his season was like
here last year? Uh we didn't really we
talked during the season honestly. Me
and Kenlaw have always kept in touch. Um
so I mean that's my dog bro. That's my
man's bro. I I rock with Kenlaw. Um so
he kind he put me down like here and um
how last season was and um so we're
we're both super excited. He came down
the cafeteria. I told him I was here and
we we talked and chopped it up. So I'm
just happy to be here.
>> Oh yeah man. I love Moo man. Charles
man. If closing cuz we know you've had a
busy day man. We know you got to go
celebrate with your loved ones, man.
Looking at ISO camera right there and
give these Commanders fans a message on
what they can expect from you this
season.
>> Yeah, man. Uh Commanders fan first and
foremost. Um extremely excited to be
here. Um blessed and honored. Um I know
it's been a great tradition here. Um uh
it's something that I want to continue
to build on. But you're going to get a
guy that's going to go and try and hunt
the quarterback. And we're not just
trying to get regular sacks. We're
trying to get strip sacks. We trying to
impact the game. A guy with high energy.
I feel like I can just kind of like let
myself loose and be me. And that's what
y'all are going to get. You're going to
get a guy that, you know, if I have a
bad play, I'm going to try and go make a
good play for y'all. So, you got just
get a guy that wants to win, wants to uh
bring the city a Super Bowl, um, and
wants to bring the city to the best
defense in the league. And we have guys
here, and I'm just a a piece of that
puzzle. We're going to put it all
together and bring out a show.
>> Nothing more needs to be said. That's a
mic drop right there. Charles, I'm in
the building. And I love hearing about
the Super Bowls. I love this, brother.
Congratulations again, man. This is a
big deal. We're so happy to have you
here, Commanders Family. Our next man
up, part of Free Fridays, Charles Manu.
Boy, man, this was fun, man. Thank you,
dog. Yes,
>> sir. Thank you.